NOAH BERMAN

Software developer.

phone:

+1 314 680 0904

email:

noah@noahberman.org

personal site:

www.noahberman.org

github:

https://github.com/bermannoah

linkedin:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/bermannoah

SUMMARY

I am a software developer committed to using my skills to work towards social justice. I am interested in gaining experience with deploying speedy, secure apps at scale and I have experience working with various ops technologies including Digital Ocean and AWS.

SKILLS

Languages/Frameworks: Ruby, Rails, HTML/CSS, ActiveRecord Systems/practices: Digital Ocean, AWS EC2, OAuth, Let's Encrypt, Bootstrap, RSpec, Capybara, Raspberry Pi

PROJECTS

Coffee Bot + Coffee Maker Bot (solo project)

- https://coffeebot.coffee
- https://github.com/bermannoah/coffee-bot
- https://github.com/bermannoah/coffee-maker-bot

Users can track and monitor coffee brewing using a robust Slack Bot. Coffee Maker Bot adds the ability (via a Raspberry Pi) to remotely start the brewing process.

* Tech Stack: Rails, PostgreSQL, Express, Raspbian, Slack OAuth, Digital Ocean

Vicarious.li (paired project)

- https://vicarious.li
- https://github.com/bermannoah/vicarious.li

Crowdfunding platform for users to raise funds.

- * My first project using AWS, and using Let's Encrypt for on-the-fly SSL/TLS
- * Tech Stack: Rails, PostgreSQL, AWS, S3 + Paperclip (image manipulation), Bootstrap

Rales Engine (paired project)

- https://github.com/bermannoah/rales_engine

API for detailed analysis of sales data.

- * Developed with speed and accuracy in mind
- * Tech Stack: Rails, PostgreSQL

RECENT EXPERIENCE

STUDENT: Turing School of Software and Design Denver, Colorado 2016 - Present - student in the backend program, Pahlka Posse co-lead (civic tech + social justice group)

OPERATIONS MANAGER / TEACHER: Center of Creative Arts (COCA)

St. Louis, Missouri 2011, 2012, 2016

FOUNDER: Screenwriting Clinic London, UK / Remote 2014 - 2016

SPECIALIST: Apple Baltimore, Maryland 2013 - 2014

- technology evangelist / sales / tech support at a busy Apple Store

INTERN/PRODUCTION ASSISTANT: Tangent Mind St. Louis, Missouri 2010 - 2013

PHOTO EDITOR / STAFF WRITER: The University News St. Louis, Missouri 2009 - 2013

EDUCATION

Turing School of Software and Design

-Backend Engineering Cohort 1608 (Currently Attending)

The London Film School

-MA, Screenwriting

Saint Louis University

- BA, Philosophy